Evokes...
...awesome...
Excellent...a couple people coming in but I think I think we get quorum
...is ready to go so,
first foremost just to make sure on the right place getting rate performance
...cordova apps we're here to talk about really not just
cordoba apps today but a lot of this is going to apply to web
applications as well so if you're not already accord over a phone gap developer
...you're still in the right place because allies lessons will still apply please,
please, please do not forget to some evaluations I take your feedback extremely
seriously I speak a lot and one my presentation to me better so,
please like...your feedback let-me know how things went.
If you are here today it's
because you probably spend enough time working on mobile applications that you care
...least enough to spend the next our learning how to
...milliseconds off of users experience of your
app so like seriously.
Give yourself a round of applause year like deep enough into it,
yeah, you care about for awesome...but,
today we want to change some of the perceptions that may be out there that
cordova apps or web applications just can't cut it when
it comes to kind of native like performance because
it can do it can do it why because of science right.
So, here's the deal this talk here is really the result of about
three months of science experiments where we really kind of went out and
talk to developers analyze some apps saw some kind
of basic problems in essential coding patterns with
...applications that we went out we talk to kind of some of
the bigger and best framework developers out there the ion...of the world's in the
...the world...the when js of the world and learn how they did it and then
kind of compared common practices to best practices to see whether or not
those differences actually resulted in meaningful perf differences so we can
better understand what exactly it is about cordova that sometimes,
you know, positive edge a little bit one thing I'm going to say
...guys this is a relatively like, you know,...strong group and
developers in the room I want this talk to be a practical talk
...conversation among developers let's geek out for the next
...if you want to interrupt me and ask questions please do so I'll repeat it for
the room and let's just like learn how to be smarter better developers goal
the awesome so it all right let's just start with a little bit
of the basics just to level set for those of you that not are not already familiar
with cordova here's the basic idea is essentially web application
...html css and javascript but, it lives inside of
...view and it gets access to native device capabilities do these things called
plugins when I say needham device capabilities what I really mean or things...the
...geo location accelerometer device contacts things like
that the basic model like I said is that it lives inside as web view because it lives inside of
a web view it needs to communicate through the native code the
...asynchronous call that asynchronous call basically talks to the native
code the native code returns backer response in the case of the camera just to make things simple
and returns back base sixty-four encoded image or reference to the file uri
in the library and then your web that can go about doing its business
you typically not always but typically all of the html css
and javascript is package with the application so that your web app
your hybrid app can also operate and offline scenarios
as well so the first part of the talk here today is going to focus really on kind of the
cordoba piece of it the second half of the talk today will apply to cordova but
it will plight equally well to web applications if that's your primary focus
at all right so before we can get into
like what is good performance let's define what we mean by snap-in...
and responsive so typically there's a lot of different kind of classifications
for this but if you kind of average it all-out people typically think about performance
...interaction classes are categories over towards the far
left-hand side of this chart you'll see fluid that's seventeen
milliseconds if you do the math that really calculates to about sixty frames per
second that sound familiar world trying to chase after that and
...sixty frames per second so that fluid class is less
...bound user interaction with your app and more about
users perception of your apps...is animations and transitions...the like one to
the right instantaneous this is really about when you touch and
...kind of the screen and maybe the button automatically lights up
or you touch and drag and the objects sticks to your finger or use
...and you get a smooth transition so that's kind of
...that fifty seventeen hundred millisecond category the golden somewhere probably around fifty
to sixty milliseconds one to the...you've got fast this would be
for macro level interactions that change large parts of you
...your ui so think about this as a navigation event if you
will and everything to the right and that you better throw up a spinner this is where things
are getting really long and maybe this is because you've got to make a
data call over the wire or you've got to do some heavy data processing
in the background today what we really care about is the far left-hand side
and this chart because frankly everything beyond two
hundred fifty milliseconds there's no question that html
...as javascript web technologies are able to handle it it's
really kind of in that far left-hand sides that's we're going to focus?
Our recent earlier methodology basically went
talk to folks like you compared against some of the best developers and framework
makers out there and that essentially gave us a and
...the way all of the tests that we performed here in
order to compare it against ios android windows we chose
three relatively compare will pieces of hardware that aren't the newest
aren't the greatest but they were pretty gosh darn good when they came out like two years ago
wanted-to years ago so all of the experiments were conducted
on these devices your mileage may vary depending upon the actual device
that your targeting but the same basic principles will apply.
So, through these experiments we got six different
kind of classes of issues...kind of
our common pitfalls the developers fall into the first one the web
...tax I'll talk about that's the one that really primarily
...cordoba development everything beyond that will apply equally well to both
...upon gap development and web development sally.
All right when the attacks.
So, I talked earlier about the basic architecture of
accord of application that runs inside of a web view and that's
wrapped inside of a native container that native container being written and
objective cfour ios java for android of fortunately native javascript
to for windows but because you run inside of a web
view there's going to be some overhead right so that's the tax
this is what you can do nothing about as a cordova
developer you just gotta pay it right so let's understand what that's about here's what we
did we said okay because accord of application is essentially a web
view inside of a native application and make sense to instantiate that web
view might have some memory overhead
...sense right so maybe the actual memory overhead for being in a
cordova app is a native application plus some browser and that equals a
...app seems intuitive right so here's what you see here this each of these orange
bars is a native application a hello world application if you will nothing
is running whatsoever and this is the memory footprint for each of
the operating systems android ios windows
...desktop and windows phone when we did is we started up a browser
this is like safari or chrome
...the case of ios android ie in the case of windows and we said all right what's the memory footprint
...just the browser displaying about blank
ok so a plus b equals c
native plus browser equals cordova not-so-fast that's actually
not the case what kind of I want you to pay attention here
...skip over android for a second ios windows
and windows phone those are kind of the cordova app is roughly
equivalent to the native app or at least not so far away that it becomes
really dangerous the far left-hand side and that giant world trade
center tower that is the android memory footprint I want you to remember that for
...actually remember the next hour or...lives even?
All right so here's the thing
...I started talking about memory but you guys maybe saying memory and
got nothing to do with performance...invisible to the user you're absolutely
right but it does have an impact on the user one place to see that is an
...time here's what we did we took each of the devices and we took
a high-speed camera filming it to hundred-forty frames per second that and we divided that,
you know, that film up into...stills each of those
stills being roughly equivalent to four milliseconds.
Then we went from the exact start time of the touch and
maybe a little bit hard to see on the screen but when I'm touching that hello world app the icons
got a little bit of a glow well-rounded on the left-hand side
on the right-hand side you can start to see the can zoom effect that's going in that means that
the app is initialize...and starting up counted the number of frames
in-between start and launch hundred thirty three frames times four milliseconds per
framed equals five hundred thirty two milliseconds and this particular example.
So, let's take a look at what the actual results were so on
the ios and notice the asterisk next to iowa's cold for just a second that
digg tower...want to caveat moment but for ios and,
windows phone and windows store the results were roughly the equivalent of
the native app right on the android side you've got to large towers
there's green bars or the cordova app cordoba apps so your startup time
...android where there was a significant memory footprint was much slower
...that's not-so-good that's one heck of attacks to have to pay
the large bar that's there for ios native I want to
caveat with the asterisk by saying because we
use the default hello world template for ios and
then default template has a build ten five hundred millisecond delay before launch
that most developers would override and that length of time probably isn't
accurate probably want to go back and retest that because my guess is if we retested it
would be much lower for each of the platforms as well you'll see that there's a cold
...warm start cold start basically means that we
completely shut down the device then started up the device and immediately started the application
of warm start means that we started up the
device then started up the application then shut down the application
...reopened the application there are can
startup time differences clearly between the warm and cold in some cases so
you got a bit of attacks here to pay particularly in the android ecosystem as a
cordoba developer there's just not much you can do about that but for ios
...for windows?
Good times right all right
so started time is not the only place where you pay attacks though in the
cordoba ecosystem there's also that bridge that you have to make between your web coding
or native code right we had to make that plug-in call over the native code to go
get the camera data or the geo location of accelerometer data or
whatever it was so here's what we did we
...dumbing plug-in that plugins only purpose in this great big world was just
to receive data and send it back...do anything complicated just received it
and sent back and we measured the amount of time that
it takes to kind of travel over and back from that bridge.
And,...without, without a pretty linear
progression in the amount of time that it took as the amount of
data increased here's the kind of important point I want to make here.
To transfer a ten to
fifteen megabyte image across that across that bridge.
It's in that two to three hundred millisecond range
...other words it is and what you would call like the fast range and
...previous interaction classes transfer anything like geo
location data accelerometer data that...you're back in the for the
...millisecond territory right so it's
below instantaneous it's like super super-fast so
can the take away that at least I got from this was that bridging that when
view was pretty much free write it didn't serve
appreciably impact performance at all and that's great news that means that the perfect tax that
you pay for being a cordova app is virtually
nil except for in the android startup case and that's only for startup
ok so let's move on to the larger class
...performance issues that we found both
...apps and with web apps and these are a lot of the same issues because
...frankly your cordova app really is a web application just running and...of a web view
...a native container...the first-place we're...go to is the dom we all know
...love the dom just as much as we love our seahawks they are
...the objects that...application and make ui right?
...we're going to I'm going to show you guys in demo this
is one instance the experiments we ran I want to be clear all
the experiments we ran we random thousands of times
...quick we ran those thousands of times in order to get a kind
of nice statistically relevant sample size what I'm going to show you
is one of those instances and I'm going to show it specifically on android
device that is tethered to my pc and then I've got
...application called...zen which essentially does screen casting back to
the desktop so every use everything you see is actually going to be performed in this case I believe
here we go...so this first one is comparing a simple dom versus
a complex...what I'm doing is open up
the tools for patchy cordoba here and we're going to have a couple of different
...and one of these guys were going to be launching and,
kind of modifying a relatively simple dom that has an about
a hundred elements are not too deeply nested next one will be using the xthree actually
will have a complex dom with many more elements and will be injecting
them and modifying them using three different techniques one of them using
...which shoving as a string the other one using kind of
a pen child and document create our create element and then the final
one using documents fragments where we make the modifications outside of
the dom and then injected wholesale into the dom as one action?
In the consul here I'm outputting the results and you'll see that for each one of them I
have a median an average them capturing when you're doing...that's generally the median that you want
to go after and right there what...just a moment to highlight
that notice that the median for the simple dom modification is and,
that amounts to a point zero to sex...point zero
two six milliseconds I know that's not much there's not much at all but...keep that
in mind because it's going to when you compare it to the complicated
...the complex dom using and html.
Which is that point zero five four or nearly double that
value those small numbers are going to add up big-time?
Later on so if you take anything away from this particular
experiment it shouldn't be that the fewer the number of elements that you have.
...been...wrestle...sweet success
...stillness that sounds awesome maybe afterwards.
If you take anything away from this really reduce the number of elements that you've got on the
page and reduce the complexity of your...let me give you...code example of what would look like.
That looks pretty normal that looks pretty friendly just a list item with
...tags but when you're making decisions to
optimize for performance the decisions that you make are not going to be the same that
you make for code ledge ability or even kind of
...any of that in this case I actually reduce the number
elements inline dom by about three percent so just by re
appropriated those list items and attaching
...event to them right so not entirely intuitivefrom
...of an initial code ledge ability perspective but from a perspective really,
really important...layout thrashing so,
this is basically the basic idea here is that we're going to
have a loop and at the point where we set a cs
as value and we're also going to read that
seitz value directly from the dom that is called layout
thrashing because as you go through that loop every single time you're going
to have to make both a query to your layout engine to say what's my size
and then you're going to reset canoeing those over and over and over
again it can really kind of tax you what's...see other works.
Same principles apply again I'm going to launches...the next is nine and notice here
...on the left-hand side I'm selling it...I'm reading it on the right-hand side inside
of it for loop then I've got another experiment
where this time what I do is I'm going to read it and one for loop and then I'm
going to set another for loop by essentially storing those values into an array
here's what we're going to do and this first...first one here we've got.
This is the one we're going to do thrashing.
And, look, at the amount of time that took that took nearly four seconds three thousand eight
hundred fourteen milliseconds then I just reset and then I did the
fast method only taking fifty-six milliseconds pause this...you can see it so that's
slow is what I'm doing a for loop where I'm setting it and reading it on either
side the fast one is where you first
...to read it and then a second loop...that cut my time by
is at twenty percent on...not good at math...percent something like that no even less
the like that's five percent right.
So, huge improvement just by refactoring your code a little bit there.
All right back over this guy so you take any
...away from this piece of it bachelor operations together.
...and don't do this?
A good work right batching together.
All right so we talked a little bit earlier about the number of elements
...complexity of your dom really kind of impacting
the performance of your app and one of the places where that manifests kind
of most obviously is when you've got a long
list of thousands of items and you try to scroll through them quickly now there's a
mostly I'm sure are familiar with a thing called virtualization the basic concept of virtualization
has this you've got a screen.
And, rather than load and all going to call it a thousand elements
...instead you just lowden those elements that are visible in the current
screen plus maybe two or three screens on either side of it
and all the other elements typically get replaced with a single dummy
element and therefore doesn't have all the children elements or some other trick in
order to maintain the scroll position good example of that many of you I'm sure
are familiar with facebook and when you first kind of bring up the mobile application you might see
and gray box there before the content actually loads n and then kind
of as you scroll down you might see other great boxes appear when you scroll quickly until they
lowden that little magic trick is called virtualization here's what we're going
...we're going to look at?
We're going to look at a virtualization...compared to a
non virtual liza list where we are essentially seeing what happens when you
got thousands upon thousands of elements in the job and a
non virtualization list and then the second one...a virtual as those
...that dom has been programmatic
...simplified and through virtualization in order to provide a
better user experience and this particular case I'm going to be using when js?
Art at the first one loading here and if I'm not mistaken this is the
non virtualization list so...got my...nine here I'm scrolling, scrolling,
scrolling all...that whole thing just turned white right the reason it
turns white is because the rendering engine just can't keep up with it
there's it's as your scrolling the paint cannot happen
fast enough because the web view the kind of the browser
is it's got too much to do is got too many elements to try to calculate okay so that was the
non virtualization let's see what the user experiences like inside of the virtual
lifeless and the virtualization here once again I'm
using when js you're still going to get a little bit of that I'll
call it tearing right but this time instead of getting kind of it mt blank
wide-screen that looks like the applications just become unresponsive instead
we're...says we're going to see some...boxes that show up?
...little other now it's up.
Commercialized list...great boxes that show up and those
great boxes in terms of providing feedback to help users no, yeah,
you can see m kind of the...boxes come up with the bottom there areas
...super super-fast I believe this list of
I'm not mistaken might have had another thousand ten thousand elements
...so you still end up with some of the
...a few elements that are not visible but because your application is providing
feedback is letting the user no like hey there's contents that...loading and
here the perception is far greater and far better all right
let's shut that one down before we have to watch wrestle...again.
And, here I talked early about the kind of the memory footprint remember android how that
giant's kind of bar came up and we had a slower start time here you can
see kind of memory correlating with the performance of the non virtualization
the virtual aasl...in this case the virtual as list has about what is that about
a third so of the memory footprint of the non virtual licensed and that's due
in large part to kind of the reduced number of elements that are in the job.
Awesome okay so take away here use virtualization
a lot of kind of popular control frameworks provide this iconic when js can
...ui on...ui all those guys provide virtualization
...should use it is really hard stuff to write you really
need a team working on this is not a ...yourself kind of thing.
I would want to rolla myself ok images this is another...excellent example
of when you've got maybe a different decision it would make.
For performance then you would make for kind of convenience and here's
...so the last five years so see sss made a lot of strides that
make it way easier to do the stuff that we used to do in photoshop directly in
the css and gradients aregreat example of that now if you want to
...you don't always have to go and created...photo
shop and then create like a one pixel tiled put out there you can just create a
...nc ss well let's see what the perf differences between these two
guys so for this one what I'm going to do...I'm going to take an image...an image
...and the first case I believe the first one uses a css
...if I'm not mistaken you see we've got here for each of the different major
kind of browsers and the second one I've got a dave where the gradient has been created
...bitmap
...do is I'm going to animate that guy across the screen for this one I'm bringing up my girlfriend the
...development tools to do a perf measurement of it since this is an android device and
for those of you that may be have not use the perf pro profiling tools and side of.
...of chrome...
...bars there node margin tell you what
your frames per second are posit so we can actually see it...marketing
with the frames per second are you do not want those bars to be tall the
taller the bars are the lower your frames per second and that's going to provide a
more stuttering type of experience you want low bars ones that are
...to the ground in the can you see the left-hand side we've got
frames per second that are well below thirty frames per second guessing at its
worst to that was probably twenty nine fifteen frames per second maybe
even less than that on the right-hand side when...animated in the image
we're getting frames per second that are closer to forty five to sixty frames
per second that's all...right there that's magic.
Let me give you can why I think that is and I...kind of
...under the hood and chrome righty to confirm this but I think is
going on here is that in the case of css as its animate
ing that gradient it has to recreate the bitmap on each frame.
And, the case...the image that bitmap has already been created
once and it just needs to move it from position a...position...so
...re calculating that bitmap on each frame is super painful and causes significant
degradation performance so when
you're optimizing for performance you may want to end up using
an image for your gradients rather than see assess and this comes not just for gradients
themselves but also for drop shadows or anywhere else that a
...might be used...exit...of this...
All right back over to it so.
Yeah, so, the question was what I apply the same principle to my j query animations
and generally yes I would you really I've not done
a test on this with the passively so, I would want to do a test to see if the
opacity if it plays differently but,
certainly like this holds universally to be true.
All right so bad and don't do this?
Good developer...animation
all right so animation this is really all about getting that seventeen
millisecond sixty frames per second thing and I know before we were talking about images and
css this is going to apply to elements however using those elements and,
really our goal here is to move
as much of the processing overrun to the gpu as possible
...javascript bing and rendering being kind of a single threaded kind of thing moving
over to the gpu clearly gives you the opportunity to do kind of doing more with multiple
threads.
Going take a look at using transform versus position and this one
I'll be honest I would guess that probably eighty percent and you in the audience might already know
this one but it's a good reminder and going to get back to fundamentals nevertheless and, this particular one what
I'm doing is I've got two different animations and the first one I
mandating using top and left although the same thing with apply for any property that
effects layout margin padding
...anything that is going to work cause a re
flow and your document model and the second one I'm going to animate using
the css so let's hear first one actually the first reminded using
css that was using translate x and y using three-d transforms.
Okay, and, that one yourselves salt I got nice
low bars now I'm animated using position and
...all these waken tall bars all along the way that's because the browsers having to
re calculate layout with each one of those so when your
animated if it were not already employee obvious to you please,
please, please use transform use translate rather than anything that's going
to affect layout it's going to reduce your frames
...actually increase your frames per second doubled try fold.
That was...transform yes sir.
All right so bad and don't do this?
Translate.
All right now.
There's another way that you can animate in german here print was just talking about using animation
...javascript and we do all the time it's a great thing to do there are some real practical
use cases besides just kind of the convenience of saying fade and fade out
that you might want to use javascript animation, for example, when you need to
redirect and animation...stream and you don't necessarily want to have a just a
pre calculated animation...fires all the time so
a is not necessarily the case that you will always only want to use
css animation there's some real you
can use cases for javascript but what are the best ways to knew that when we need
...using javascript so in this particular one we've got?
A couple of different types of animation we're going...do in this particular one we're using
...a set timeout and then by
an interval right so we're just kind of iterating every sixty frames per second either using a set
...resetting...or the...du-rable
then we've got another one that's going to use the request animation frame from your see
...timer and...got another one again that's just going to use a pure css animation
everyone familiar with request animation frame
essentially the for those that don't know request animation frame is essentially a timer
that runs in css and it's kind of the css equivalent of an
interval that's running and but it doesn't have to be on the javascript thread.
...so that first one I believe that one was with ...set time-out consent
enterable and all of these are using the top and left positions so were
you doing the bad practice of animated position via x and y all
of those as you might guess are getting as a frames per second of thirty
frames per second or less so not very good the next...going to do here when I love this
...believe this is where chrome actually kind of bugs out and gets weird results so,
now we're estimating the...animation and it's kind of hard to see all
the actually you cannot see all of the bars because they're just not rendering correctly and,
I do it multiple times trying to get chrome to actually render correctly but,
that css animation is super fluid in this one we're actually getting frames per
second that are round sixty frames per second maybe even a little bit better...this one I finally
got...railways...threads...frames per second.
The next one here.
Is going to be with request animation frame so I was a bad boy
...not actually record the request information frame I'm sorry about that I
can't say the results though because I did it a thousand times over
the request animation frame is the exact same frames per second that should get
was css so even though it's done programmatic
...via ...javascript and you're just setting at the setting in this case
my translate three-d on each frame because I'm using the css interval the
request animation frame to manage my loop I get way better
performance right so if you take anything away from this take
this away use item request animation frame or css when
you can the benefits there are just magnificent?
Garbage collection everybody loves the garbage collector takes on the dirty stuff away
right.
garbage collector ...actually got many years of the browsers perfecting
...garbage collection they actually do a pretty gosh darn good job and they kind of when we
remover elements from the dom they removing completely and we don't accrue any kind of memory
...but in fact the matter is that you can
...yourself into a corner where the garbage collector doesn't know where to
find your trash what net results and is accrued memory over
time and we've all seen over the course the last thirty minutes so what happens when you accrue memory
over time your performance generally starts to degraded over time as well and,
browsers this is less of a big deal because frankly
your tearing down your browser every time you navigate to a new page it's
...to complete memory dump but when you're
na cordoba application where you rarely shut down the application I
don't know...you guys but I can have applications running for weeks or even months
before actually restart my phone that kind of accrued memory
get over time can be very painful?
Let's try this first one and this particular one here's what I'm going to
do I'm going to create a bunch of elements I'm going to attach
an event listener to them and then I'm going to get rid
of the elements just by doing energy html equals quote
another words encouraging the element but I still have all of those and
then listeners and...the functions that are associated with them hanging around
so still on my android device want to go back over the...deb tools this time I'm going to do
...memory analysis of what I'm doing here...just creating and, attaching those
and listeners...destroying the elements...want you to pay attention to
in this ramp right here that's slowly growing.
That ramp is performance death.
Right that's just your memory growing and growing and growing until eventually
your application will slow to a crawl and it will happen
your application will eventually just straight up crash the browser now I know
that I was adding thousands and thousands of elements very quickly at a time but as I said before if
you got an application that's up and running over the course of multiple
weeks or months and you do lots of navigation leaving those of
...handlers around that can be very bad so.
Being good remove the event listeners make sure that
you've kind of eliminated all you're dead so that your memory does not grow over time.
Bad and don't do this right don't leave those
...listeners hanging around?
Go ahead and be responsible remove
that event listener remove that element directly from the dom using the tools that the browser gave you.
All right now when it comes to
...is also important to minimize the total number of
event listeners because each one of those functions has
a memory footprint and your application and there's a
couple of different ways to do this so one way and I do this all the time I'm sure all
of you do as well I've got a
for loop I've got an array of elements and I just loop through that array of elements
...say adamant listener function and then I write the function
inline and I loop through the ll through the
method again right so I end up with a one-to-one
pairing between my objects might elements
and my event listeners in their functions here's a better way to do this though
...better way to do this is essentially to use event bubbling to the magic of the
dom you can basically have a single kind of method at the top that's only on
a parent element and then you essentially have a switch case and
if statement that's in that method at the bottom that identifies
the click target and then executes that we only have one function
that handles events for everything and I know now I
know I know that from a maintain ability perspective that looks a little scary that sounds
a little scary but so long as we're in a perf talk talking about ways to
optimize for performance this is a decision you may want to make in order to
optimize for better performance over code maintain ability
eligibility right so let's see what that actually looks like here actually explain a little bit better
here you see here that I've got these objects are elements one-two-three and four I can put
in event listener on the dude and the adamant listener will basically
listen to say clique target is one execute function a
click target is to execute function be or...code segment b.
All right let's see actually see this...action and this particular one I've
got a page where we do let's here that's...up.
We're going to create a bunch of objects are of elements and for each one of those elements we're going
to first attach a actually the...was going to use the bubbling...good way first.
But, this guy get started up here I'm kind of passing through the code here so this one
...going to hit one of...the top one and
it's a little bit difficult to read but trust me what we're doing there is this is the...bubbling one.
Click on that going.
Awesome and this particular case...take a heap snapshot to see what the total memory footprint of the
application is and, this will give us an idea kind of based upon a kind of
...correlation with memory what are performance...might be all
right the next one we're going to use one event listener and one function per
elements this is the method where we had a for loopand, we just loop through our
...elements and assigned new function to it as we went to the loop each time.
They...snapshot too and then finally this last
approach that we're going to do this is going to have a for loop again but instead
...time defining are function...we're going to reference back to
a single function that's been identified separately elsewhere
what I want you to pay attention to on...highlight in just a second is look,
at...this number rate here this is this it's about eight percent of the
...total memory allocation that's and, the correlating to two hundred fifty seven
kilobytes this one is in double this is the one event listener and
one function per object...this is the event bubbling one again back down to two
fifty seven so by creating
an unique function for each event listener and each object we effectively doubled the
overall memory footprint of the application and here you'll see I'm kind of opening it up and,
you'll actually see the amend listener and the prototype function that's associated with each one of the
objects even though each of those only has two hundred sixty four kilobytes
associated with each one frames bites truancy for bites with each one because that
adds up over time and creative significant footprint on your application.
So, if you take anything away from this.
I would say take advantage of event bubbling or failing that if you're not going to take advantage
...that bubbling in least reference back to a
common function and use that common function to kind of sort things out from
there don't try to stamp out and replicate your method for each object.
So, the...we...that for loop there were can
assigning in creating a new function for each object good.
Reference back to a and sort of...function that's defined elsewhere
are use and then bubbling and the side of your dom right.
Ok, pay attention...memory leaks so,
this is kind of similar to the lesson we saw earlier with when we can
...dom but we leftover...listeners there but in this case it's kind of the
html element corollary to it?
...open this guy up.
And, this case what's actually going to happen is that and the first case we're going
to have objects that mapped to a private function so
when we navigate and we can get rid of the that function
all the objects are going to die with it in other words they won't be kind of orphaned and,
...dom right and the second case
we're going to attach all of those two a global name space and because it's in
a global namespaces when the private method dies all of the objects will still
be sticking around and because they're in the global name space polluting that name space
there just memory dead again so in this case I'm navigating back and forth and like I
said and this one were attaching all the objects to a private method
...lifetime will expire with the navigation event.
Here we take a snapshot of in the chrome dem tools.
And, you'll see here I'm going...look at my
html development there and it's nice and clean there's nothing superfluous
there all of those elements are actually being used in my dom actively
at that moment this next one I'm going to do the same thing but like I
said this time all of those elements are attached to a global variable
that global variable because this is a single page application does not expire with
a navigation event so I just did that in this case by removing the var declaration
inside of the function automatically placing it in the global name space.
So, here we go again we're going to do launched the application and do
...theoretically that should if you were
...a private name space it would have gotten rid of all those objects?
I'm going to fast-forward a little bit because, you know, what navigation looks like?
Okay,
here we go and just doing a second heap snapshot of it and that
particular one now when you look in the dem tools you see all those elements that are
read can get like a pink highlighting to them that means that those
are orphaned elements that exist only in memory but do not exist and
the dom you don't want that over time those guys are just going to build-up and build-up
and build-up especially in this case was on a simple navigation event and that's just going to
low-down your application and...get sluggish over time.
All right we're closing in on the and here.
So, the destroy all those unused objects keep amount of the global name space when, you know,
that you're not going to use them anymore responsibly remove them from the from the page.
This casey var ll is...the global name space and then I'm creating it and
then potentially destroying at a private method.
Good on both creating it and eventually I could destroy it
inside of the private method so it's not going as ling...that global name space
goal and awesome all right last little bit of
it here so this is an interesting experiment because I've.
Actually talked to several people in the last week about this experiment so some of
the may be familiar with this thing called fast clicking so a lot of
a versions of operating systems particularly in cordoba apps this is really relevant
cordova abs a native application
when you touch immediately fires the click event usually within
...less than fifty milliseconds let's call it but for what were
some actually relatively good reasons in browsers they delay that click event by
three hundred milliseconds ostensibly the primary reason is that us
...done this before you...double tap...your web browser because you want
zoom into the html text that's a good usability feature right but the fact
the matter is that in a native application are...application you want
...feel more like a native application so you don't want that three hundred millisecond
delay when you double when you click you wanted to automatically register as a click event
...are number of frameworks out there that have been designed to kind
of solve this problem by essentially mapping the click event to the on touch
event or the on mouse down event depending upon whether it was a touch device
or click device one of the most popular these is called fast click dot js?
So, we did a bunch of experiments trying to reproduces thriller millisecond delay
all be honest and our experiments we were not able to replicated
I feel like we must have done something wrong
...each there it is we were not able to...millisecond delay and fear you'll actually see it.
I'm going to launch an application on my in this particular demo it's
...nine but recall that most of our hard experiments
...seven for the android device and, a and, air
for ios and a windows nine thirty I think for windows and what you're going to see
...you're going to see when I touch this minimum touching this with my finger on the actual device I
see the touch start the mouse down events...the click
...in the delay that you see between there and you'll see them getting what on click event
I'm getting anywhere between fifty and a hundred milliseconds
mass down seventy-four touch start zero...don't get me wrong
eighty-two hundred-seventy milliseconds is not nothing there's still a
delay there but it is not the three hundred millisecond kind of
that I've at least been led to believe so we're going to do a little bit more research into this
to better understand it as I said before this is part of an experiment in a series of
experiments that we've been running over the last three months and we intended continue...a question over here?
That could be I don't believe we have
...tag on there though I like we tried to strip it down to the to the bare minimum.
No, because it...it immediately registers it so,
touch was one percent...looks awesome all right.
Okay,
cool so what kinda...the end of it I hope you guys
have learn something I hope that if it was a review that it was helpful review if you
leave this room today thinking anything like
honestly anyone can build slow apps it's totally easy to build a crappy app you can do
and any language but, you don't have to whether it's objective csharp.
Javascript anything you can build a nice snappy...map and,
I hope that you'll be able to use...of the
...today to make your apps better and if you got any interesting experiments that
your conducting please let-me know I'm on twitter at ryan geis
...and you can talk with the product team at
...tools on twitter as well there are slides
...practical advice at the end these we posted online I will not rehash the
last our with you now does anyone ask questions kind-of here at the end.
Yeah, so, the question is are there any static analysis tools for these types of defects so,
there are some lynching tools that are out
there for it I do not have any to recommend but certainly one-of-a-kind
our future research projects is to figure out what's
out there and plug holes and what is not so we can start to provide some of the
static analysis tools to provide better guides developers at the time of coding?
So, when js already provides kind of a
for their basic controls optimization to make sure that you're kind of getting the
event immediately other than that all of the events are not specific to when js at least
...the best of my knowledge but rather just baked into kind of the platform?
So, I would continue I believe that when js
kind of does the same trick that fast click does to associate click with the
...mass downs that you don't have a delay once again our tests and
...were on tests on a that one devices not ten devices but the
when js framework is the...whether you're...and eight-point one or ten
we were not able to find a significant delay using any of the default controls ...
Yeah, so, the question was can I touch upon the impact of aim the more common
or popular frameworks online performance I will say that the filament
group did a fabulous analysis comparing angular react I believe
there third one was backbone?
Certainly I would say that reacts definitely has
in there study it won out over angular but
not necessarily substantially so with angular to dot co and
written angular one that three an above they are really,
really optimizing for mobile first rather than desktop so
they're making like huge
...to not just providing little impact to the
perf but also providing easy...paths to fall into the pit
of success with perf I can tell you one of the biggest
dangers that icy and enterprise environment's
is that over time we say how manual...this
...feature this framework over here has that feature and then we
know two weeks later want to add another feature so we add maybe another little library another
little framework so what you end up seeing over the course of three to six months
and an enterprise environment particularly is that you start to layer on
j query plus angular plus something else and something else
...plug-in here another something there so layering
frameworks on top of each other can be absolute death to the per from
...application the other thing that I would say is that as
...considering frameworks and in the cordova plug-in world as well it's
really anything opensource please make sure and then you are.
Are really responsibly evaluating
the quality of the framework the plug-in that you're usingyou can
use some good proxies for that you can look at the number of downloads for
it you can look at the number of contributions the number of people who are
current contributing and when the last contribution was we had
customers using our tools recently who added in a plug-in
I happen to be the most popular plug-in for sql light and,
use inside of cordova ...for angular had lots and lots of downloads but
...the same plug-in hadn't been updated in approximately two years despite
having belong backlog pull...that were submitted to it and other words the plug-in
had deteriorated and quality over time causing terrible,
terrible perf problems and it was actually relatively simple fix to
can bring the plug-in up to speed but if
you don't monitor the quality of your frameworks...plugins that
can really kind of really where on the quality of your overall application so,
I would say to circle back around here initial question any of the more popular
frameworks out there today like the big names of the world the angular and the reacts
the backbone the...js of the world of all of these guys are optimizing
heavily for perf and I would have absolutely no qualms with incorporating into
my mobile application at that point it just becomes a matter
...stylistic preference and a matter of compatibility with your
ui control framework of choice I think I saw another question here yet?
Yeah, so, the question was he assumed correctly so
the perf analysis that we and done was on the default android web
view and if we...done a similar tasked with crosswalk the...
the question is no we've not done similar test with crosswalk yet and, I'm very much want
to is absolutely on our backlog here in the things that I can tell you about
it crosswalk has about a seventeen megabytes impact on your and,
your package size so it will increase the initial install
time from what I understand it does not have a significant impact on the
run-time memory and, for reasons that I don't entirely understand yet but I believe
that what's happening there is that because the native android application doesn't have to
spend up chrome and instead
...on device chrome and it's just able to startup the crosswalk...runtime
memory impact is about the same I have a suspicion this is not
...in science I have a suspicion that performance and crosswalk will be
better than the older default android web views
essential theoretically be using the latest version of chrome and it will
benefit from all of the purpose optimizations that you get and newer versions of...so,
that's my suspicion please stay
tuned we will be conducting experiments on this to get to the bottom of an better understand it so,
that we can all...
make better choices there there's another one that came from this general vicinity I think maybe.
Now awesome cool well, then thank you guys so,
very much for the time truly appreciated don't forget developed evaluations
and enjoy the rest your time in san francisco I hope that you have an awesome time.